eeb.org 2019-05-12

# Privacy Policy - EEB - The European Environmental Bureau

#### The European Environmental Bureau (EEB) (with headquarters at Boulevard de Waterloo 34, B-1000 Brussels, Belgium, Enterprise number BE.0415.814.848 ) is the controller of the personal data collected by EEB websites (see list below) or data gathered in the field (such as business cards, publicly available contact information, etc.) and the controller of the personal data of its members and the representatives of its members.

The EEB commits to respect the privacy of its contacts and its members and describes hereunder its privacy practices.

The personal information you provide to the EEB will be used and stored as follows:

#### **Data collection and use**

The EEB collects personal information you provide to deliver different services such as weekly information newsletters and information on campaigns (called hereinafter the Service).  The data are collected based on the EEB’s legitimate interests to keep you updated of the EEB’s activities and/or based on the contract established between you and the EEB (the association contract).   In some cases, the EEB will ask consent to inform you about fee paying activities.

The EEB strives to limit the amount of personal information collected to support the intended purpose of the collection.

The personal information collected could be used to contact you via email, telephone or mail to keep you updated of EEB events, working groups, etc.

#### **Cookies**

EEB websites use cookies – small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience.

In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.

Such information will not identify you personally it is statistical data about our visitors and their use of our site. This statistical data does not identify any personal details whatsoever.

Similarly to the above, we may gather information about your general internet use by using a cookie file. Where used, these cookies are downloaded to your computer automatically.

This cookie file is stored on the hard drive of your computer as cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive. They help us to improve our website and the service that we provide to you.

As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.

We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers

#### **  Transfer of data**

The EEB will not use, share, rent or sell your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

No data is stored or transferred outside Europe except in the case where we use a contracted data processor operating under the EU-US or EU-Swiss Privacy Shield Framework.

For auditing purposes we may show attendee lists obtained at events to donors for the sole purpose of verifying that funded events took place.

In relation to media contact the EEB maintain a media contacts list that is shared with the environmental NGO Transport & Environment.

#### **Service Providers**

The EEB may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:

To facilitate our Service;

To provide the Service on our behalf;

To perform Service-related services; or

To assist us in analysing how our Service is used.

These service providers include: Microsoft, Mailchimp, Dropbox etc. We only choose third-party companies that are GDPR compliant.

#### **Controlling your personal information**

Your personal information is fully accessible by contacting the EEB at the email address [eeb@eeb.org](mailto:eeb@eeb.org). We can also transfer the data collected pursuant to the association contract to another association (data portability).

If you believe that any information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible at the address [eeb@eeb.org](mailto:eeb@eeb.org). We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

If you want to be completely removed from our database or if you want a restriction of your data processing, please send an email to [eeb@eeb.org](mailto:eeb@eeb.org) or alternatively you can use the unsubscribe button which may be contained in the communication. If you are a member of the association, be aware that the fact that you ask to be removed from our database or to limit our access to your data, makes us unable to convene you to the meetings or other activities of the association.

If you are concerned that we have not complied with your legal rights or applicable privacy laws, you may contact the CPP (Commission for the Protection of Privacy [www.privacycommission.be](http://www.privacycommission.be/)) (which is the regulator responsible for data protection in Belgium, where the EEB is located).

Alternatively, if you are located outside of Belgium, you may contact your local data protection authority.

#### **Period of storage**

EEB will store your information as long as you use our Services or you are member of our network and until five year after your last use of our Services or the termination of the membership.

#### **Children’s Privacy**

Our Services do not address anyone under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from children under 16. In the case we discover that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information, we immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact us so that we will be able to take necessary actions.

#### **Security**

We take precautions to protect your information both online and offline. Only employees who need the information to perform specific actions are granted access to personally identifiable information.

The computers/servers on which we store personally identifiable information are protected and kept in a secure environment.

#### **Applicant data**

The EEB is committed to protecting the privacy and personal data of job applicant data. The treatment of this data is covered under the EEB Recruitment Privacy Statement which is available[ here.](https://eeb.org/eeb-recruitment-privacy-statement/)

#### **Update**

This policy is updated from time to time. The latest version is available on this page and has been published on May 20 2018. We advise you to review this page periodically for any changes. These changes are effective immediately, after they are posted on this page.

#### **Contact**

If you have any questions about this policy, please email to [eeb@eeb.org](mailto:eeb@eeb.org) or write to: The European Environmental Bureau, Boulevard de Waterloo 34, B-1000 Brussels, Belgium.

#### **List of websites managed by the EEB**

eeb.org, meta.eeb.org, metamag.org, eebconference.eu, zeromercury.org,  makeresourcescount.eu, sdgwatcheurope.org, makeeuropesustainableforall.org, sdgtoolkit.org, envjustice.org, digi-label.com, pocketwatt.eu, coolproducts.eu

This list relates to actively managed sites controlled by the EEB. There are a small number of archived websites that are controlled by the EEB but are not actively managed and do not collect data.
